<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<config-description xmlns="http://jfreereport.sourceforge.net/namespaces/config-description">
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.FailOnAttributeExpressionErrors">
    <description>Defines whether attribute-expression evaluation errors cause the report processing to fail with an
      error. Use this to prevent errors in calculated fields from producing invalid reporting results.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.FailOnStyleExpressionErrors">
    <description>Defines whether style-expression evaluation errors cause the report processing to fail with an error.
      Use this to prevent errors in calculated fields from producing invalid reporting results.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ReportInstancesShareConnections">
    <description>Defines whether subreports share their datasource per instance or per declared subreport.</description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.WatermarkPrintedOnTopOfContent" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines whether the watermark band is printed on top of all content (true, overlaying the page content)
      or whether it shall be printed beneath the page content (false, default)
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.UseNativeScaling" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines whether image scaling in the reporting engine uses the built-in Graphics2D scaling or a slower
      but higher quality algorithm that scales images in several steps to reduce artifacts.

      Defaults to true as most people prefer speed over quality.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.DetectExtraContent" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines whether the reporting engine will treat elements carrying non-printable information, like
      anchor names or html-extra-raw-content as content elements. If set to true, these elements will compete with all
      other elements for space in the table.

      Defaults to true to solve the case where a empty element has extra content and where it would not appear unless
      that extra content is detected.

      Set to false to restore the PRD-3.6 behaviour. Make sure your extra-content elements generate some sort of output
      or they will not be included in the final report output.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>


  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ResourceBundle" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>The default resource-bundle that should be used when no explicit bundle is defined.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.AllowOwnPeerForComponentDrawable" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, that components drawn in a Component-Element or a ComponentDrawable are allowed to supply
      their own window-object as native peer. Allowing foreign peers can lead to very strange behaviour, ranging from
      unpredictable effects in the UI of the calling programm to even memory leaks.

      This property defaults to false.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ComponentDrawableMode" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines how the system processes AWT-components. Possible values are:

      &apos;private&apos; - All components get their own peer. This may result in problems on Windows. If you receive
      the message &apos;No more handles available&apos;, switch back to &apos;shared&apos; mode.

      &apos;synchronized&apos; - All components get their own peer, but all drawing operations will be executed on the
      AWT-EventDispatcher thread. This may result in problems on Windows. If you receive the message &apos;No more
      handles available&apos;, switch back to &apos;shared&apos; mode.

      &apos;shared&apos; - All components of a given report share a single AWT-peer. All drawing operations will be
      executed on the AWT-EventDispatcher thread.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>private</text>
      <text>synchronized</text>
      <text>shared</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterAutoSubmit" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>A global setting on whether parameter UIs should have their Auto-Submit feature enabled by default or
      not.

      This property defaults to false.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
      <text>prompt</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterAutoSubmitUI" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines the default value for the auto-submit checkbox in parameter-UIs, if the autosubmit parameter is
      set to prompt.

      This property defaults to true.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterAutoFillsSelection" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines whether list-parameter without a value default to the first value in the list of available
      values.

      This property defaults to false.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterUiLayout" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines the layouting strategy for the parameter UI. This can be either one of

      vertical - (default) all parameter are layouted along the y-axis,
      horizontal - all parameter are layouted along the x-axis with no linebreak or
      flow - all parameter are layouted along the x-axis with potential linebreaks if the end of the available
      space is reached.
      This property defaults to vertical.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>vertical</text>
      <text>horizontal</text>
      <text>flow</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <!--
org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterAutoSubmit=prompt
org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterAutoSubmitUI=true
org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ParameterUiLayout=vertical
  -->
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ConfigStore" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Where to store cached configuration data</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.DataSchemaDefinition.built-in.core" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal Configuration setting. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.DebugDataSources" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines whether datasources should provide additional log messages. As this kind of logging can result
      in large amounts of data it is set to &apos;fase&apos; as default. Set it to &apos;true&apos; to enable the
      logging.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.DynamicStrokeDashes" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the stroke dashs should take the pen width into account or whether the stroke dashes
      should always be static.

      The static version was the default until JFreeReport 0.8.7-4 and has been changed to the more sensible dynamic
      model since that version.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.EnableBrokenImage" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>This property defines if a broken image icon should be displayed for elements whose images are missing.

      This property is disabled by default to preserve full backward compatiblity.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.EnableGlobalSubReportImports" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>This property defines how global * imports from subreports to their master-reports are handled. If the
      subreport contains rows with the same name as the parent, this feature will mask the parent&apos;s fields making
      them unavailable once the subreport executed.

      In general, there should be no need to ever enable this feature, and if you do you are on your own. Passing data
      from subreports to master reports should be done by explicit mappings carefully avoiding any duplicate columns.

      This setting defaults to &quot;false&quot;.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.FixImageResolutionMapping" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines that the layouter uses the System&apos;s native resolution to compute the size of images. This
      fixes problems with the HTML output, which assumes that images are rendered with a resolution of 96dpi.

      This setting defaults to true. To make use of it, the Device-Resolution configuration setting has to be defined as
      well.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.LastLineBreaksOnWordBoundary" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the last line will only print complete words. If set to true, the ellipse (the &apos;..&apos;)
      will remove the last incomplete word before printing the dots. If set to false, the engine will print as much
      characters as possible without overlapping with the ellipse.

      Defaults to &quot;true&quot;.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.NoPrinterAvailable" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether JFreeReport should query the default page format from the printerdriver. If there is
      no printer installed on Windows, this seems to block the JavaVM until a time out is reached.

      If this property is set to &quot;true&quot; a hard coded default page format is used instead. By default, the
      engine assumes that a printer is available and therefore this property defaults to &apos;false&apos;.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ProfileDataSources" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines whether datasources should log performance metrics. This logging can also be used to measure
      the execution time of queries. This setting defaults to &apos;false&apos; by default.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ProfileReportProcessing" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the report processor should print performance related data during the report
      processing. This defaults to false, but can savely be set to true to get more details on the report performance.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.LogRowProgress" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the report processor should print performance related data during the report
      processing.
      This defaults to false, and if enabled prints a log message every 50000 rows.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.LogPageProgress" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the report processor should print performance related data during the report
      processing.
      This defaults to false, and if enabled prints a log message on every page processed.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.LogLevelProgress" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the report processor should print performance related data during the report
      processing.
      This defaults to false, and if enabled prints a log message on every processing level that has started.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.StrictErrorHandling" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines a stricter error handling, if set to &apos;true&apos;, then all errors that occur during the
      report processing will cause the report processing to fail. It is safe to set this to &apos;true&apos;, as valid
      reports never throw exceptions.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.URLEncoding" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines the character encoding that is used when encoding text for URLs. This setting default to
      ISO-8859-1 as this is the common standard.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.WarnInvalidColumns" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines, whether the datarow prints warning on invalid columns. Requests to invalid columns are non
      fatal, but these messages give usefull hints on invalid report definitions.

      If set to true, an additional logging entry is added whenever an invalid column is encountered.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.YieldRate" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines how often the report processing thread should yield to let other processes continue. Setting
      this property to a value greater than zero enables the Yield-feature and improves the overal reponsiveness of the
      application at the cost of some performance.

      This property default to &apos;100&apos;. Set it to zero to disable yielding.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.auto-report-preprocessors.Aggregate-Function-Processor"
       global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal Configuration setting. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.environment.designtime.Locale" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines a design-time locale. This locale is only active when using the DefaultReportEnvironment.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.environment.designtime.TimeZone" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines a design-time TimeZone. This TimeZone is only active when using the DefaultReportEnvironment.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.function.LogFormulaFailureCause" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>A debug-helper property that enables verbose logging for any errors which happen during formula
      evaluations. Defaults to true to give maximum insight, but for production systems this should be set to false to
      make sure that evaluation errors do not slow down the report processing.

      Defaults to &quot;true&quot;.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.DeviceResolution" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines the user-defined output-device resolution. Images will be scaled to fit this resolution if the
      setting FixImageResolutionMapping is set to true.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.ParanoidChecks" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Defines, whether the reporting engine performs additional checks on its internal data-structures.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.defaults.FontSize" global="false" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines the default font size that should be used if there is no other font-information available.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.defaults.FontSmoothThreshold" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>Defines the minimum font size in point to which Text-Antialiasing is applied if the Font-Smooth
      property is set to auto. This setting defaults to &apos;8&apos; as smaller fonts tend become unreadable with
      aliasing applied to them.
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.fontrenderer.IsBuggyFRC" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>This is a override setting. Some Graphics2D implementations have problems with the font positioning. I
      don&apos;t know a way to resolve that bug on the root, so if the bug happens to you, try setting this property to
      &quot;true&quot; to resolve wrong or buggy string draw results.

      (This property is no longer used.)
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.fontrenderer.UseAliasing" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Enable aliasing for Graphics2D. This may result is textlayout errors. If your text is not correctly
      aligned, disable this property.

      (This property is no longer used.)
    </description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.layout.fontrenderer.UseMaxCharBounds" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>The old JFreeReport way of computing line heights is not working correctly in some cases. Under some
      conditions, a character may exceed its normal line height (for instance if it is an upper case letter with
      accents). In that case, using the font size as line height is not working correctly, causing the text to be
      clipped.

      If this property is set to &apos;true&apos;, the line height is computed from the maximum character size for the
      specified font. If set to &apos;false&apos;, the line height is set to match the declared font size, so that the
      old behaviour of previous versions of JFreeReport is preserved.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>true</text>
      <text>false</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.global-includes.core-include" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>Internal Configuration setting. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.global-includes.report-designer" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>Internal Configuration setting. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.global-includes.report-designer-parser" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>Internal Configuration setting. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.action" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.core" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.crosstab" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.excel" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.html" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.internal" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.pdf" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.report-designer" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.wizard" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.namespaces.xml" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal XML parser property. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.modules.parser.data-factory-prefix.built-in.compound"
       global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.modules.parser.data-factory-prefix.built-in.sql" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.states.NullDataSourceHandling" global="true" hidden="false">
    <description>Defines how the engine behaves, if a data-factory returns null instead of throwing an exception if it
      cannot handle a query. The implementations of 0.8.9 illegally returned null and therefore several reports depend
      on the behavior that in that case an empty tablemodel is auto-generated.

      For now, we will warn that this is illegal behavior. In the next version, we will switch the property from &quot;warn&quot;
      to &quot;fail&quot; enforcing the correct behavior by default.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>warn</text>
      <text>fail</text>
    </enum>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.stylekeys.band" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.stylekeys.core-layout" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.stylekeys.element" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.stylekeys.static-layout" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.stylekeys.text" global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.util.PropertyLookupParserEscapeMode" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>Defines how the property-parser will handle escape sequences in parsed text. The property parser is
      used to inject named parameters in the format of ${name} or $(name) into parsed xml-text and queries in the
      datafactories. The property defaults to &apos;strict&apos; to maintain a sensible level of backward compatiblity
      while causing minimal impact otherwise.

      Possible values are &quot;strict&quot;, &quot;all&quot; or &quot;none&quot;.
    </description>
    <enum>
      <text>strict</text>
      <text>all</text>
      <text>none</text>
    </enum>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.external.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.jdbc.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.kettle.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.mondrian.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.olap4j.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.pmd.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.reflection.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.table.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.datasource-editor.xpath.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.modules.report-designer-parser.Module" global="true"
       hidden="true">
    <description>A module definition. Please do not edit this entry.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.ExternalDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.TableDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.modules.misc.datafactory.NamedStaticDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.modules.misc.datafactory.StaticDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.modules.misc.datafactory.sql.SQLReportDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.modules.misc.datafactory.sql.SimpleSQLReportDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.kettle.KettleDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.mondrian.BandedMDXDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.mondrian.DenormalizedMDXDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.mondrian.LegacyBandedMDXDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.olap4j.BandedMDXDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.olap4j.DenormalizedMDXDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.olap4j.LegacyBandedMDXDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.pmd.PmdDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.scriptable.ScriptableDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.metadata.datafactory-editor.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.extensions.datasources.xpath.XPathDataFactory"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>Internal DataFactory-Editor configuration. Do not modify.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.DataFactory.compound"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.MasterReport.report-designer"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.SubReport.report-designer"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.parser.DataFactoryMetaDataCollection"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.parser.ElementTypeCollection.default"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.parser.ExpressionMetaDataCollection.default"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.parser.GlobalMetaDefinition.default"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls the report-engine initialization. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key
      name="org.pentaho.reporting.libraries.resourceloader.factory.modules.org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.metadata.parser.ReportPreProcessorMetaDataCollection"
      global="true" hidden="true">
    <description>A internal configuration that controls an XML-Generator. Do not edit.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>

  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.pagestates.PrimaryPoolSize" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>A performance tuning setting</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.pagestates.SecondaryPoolFrequency" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>A performance tuning setting.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.pagestates.SecondaryPoolSize" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>A performance tuning setting.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
  <key name="org.pentaho.reporting.engine.classic.core.performance.pagestates.TertiaryPoolFrequency" global="false"
       hidden="false">
    <description>A performance tuning setting.</description>
    <text/>
  </key>
</config-description>
